Echo, The State College; Collection ua950.012
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
The State College Echo Collection
1892 June-1939 April
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
State University of New York at Albany--Students
ua950.012
2.97 cubic ft. 81 Digital Files
Collection is made up of the student publications The Echo, the State College Quarterly, and the State College Echo.
Administrative History
The Echo was first published by the students of the State Normal College in June of 1892. It original purpose was as a monthly newsletter or newspaper for the student s of the school. By the time of the second volume of publication in 1893, it had become half school news, and half a literary periodical, publishing prose and poetry written by students. This format was continued until 1918 when publication of the Echo ceased. Two years earlier the State College News, a general school newspaper, was first published. It is likely that the school newsletter aspect of the publication no longer seemed necessary.
That is why the following Fall of 1918, the State College Quarterly began as a publication solely dedicated to prose and poetry written by students. People who worked on the literary section of The Echo transferred to the new publication, and the Quarterly remained a student owned and run periodical. This version of the publication was published until the spring of 1928. There is no explanation but the following Fall, the publication changed its name to the State College Echo.
This version of the Publication maintained its literary roots, publishing poetry and prose written by the students of the State College for Teachers. Those who had worked for the Quarterly continued under the new name, and the overall organization of the periodical was maintained. The State College Echo was published until April 1939.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of the twenty-seven volumes of The Echo dating from 1892 to 1918. Some are bound by volume while others are foldered on their own. Volumes 8-13, encompassing 1900-1905, have many numbers missing from the collection. The State College Quarterly is made up of ten bound volumes dating from 1918-1928. The State College Echo section of the collection is made up of eleven volumes dating from 1928-1939, with a single duplicate edition of the November 1932 publication.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is organized into a single series and arranged chronologically within that series.
Acquisition Information
All items in this manuscript group were donated to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives.
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted.
College newspapers and periodicals; College Publications; Serial publications; UAlbany Student Groups; Digital Files; State University of New York at Albany
- The State College Echo, 1892 June-1939 April; 1; 2.97 cubic ft. 81 Digital Files
  Arrangement
  Series is arranged chronologically by publication date.
  Scope and Contents
  Materials include three separate student publications titled "The Echo," "The State College Quarterly," and the "State College Echo."
  - The Echo Volume 1 Number 1, 1892 June (Volume 1, Issue 1)
  - The Echo Volume 1 Number 2, 1892 September (Volume 1, Issue 2)
  - The Echo Volume 1 Number 3, 1892 October (Volume 1, Issue 3)
  - The Echo Volume 1 Number 4, 1892 November (Volume 1, Issue 4)
  - The Echo Volume 1 Number 5, 1892 December (Volume 1, Issue 5)
  - The Echo Volume 1 Number 6, 1893 January (Volume 1, Issue 6)
  - The Echo Volume 1 Number 7, 1893 February (Volume 1, Issue 7)
  - The Echo Volume 1 Number 8, 1893 March (Volume 1, Issue 8)
  - The Echo Volume 1 Number 9, 1893 April (Volume 1, Issue 9)
  - The Echo Volume 1 Number 10, 1893 May (Volume 1, Issue 10)
  - The Echo Volume 2 Number 1, 1893 June (Volume 2, Issue 1)
  - The Echo Volume 2 Number 2, 1893 September (Volume 2, Issue 2)
  - The Echo Volume 2 Number 3, 1893 October (Volume 2, Issue 3)
  - The Echo Volume 2 Number 4, 1893 November (Volume 2, Issue 4)
  - The Echo Volume 2 Number 5, 1893 December (Volume 2, Issue 5)
  - The Echo Volume 2 Number 6, 1894 January (Volume 2, Issue 6)
  - The Echo Volume 2 Number 7, 1894 February (Volume 2, Issue 7)
  - The Echo Volume 2 Number 8, 1894 March (Volume 2, Issue 8)
  - The Echo Volume 2 Number 9, 1894 April (Volume 2, Issue 9)
  - The Echo Volume 2 Number 10, 1894 May (Volume 2, Issue 10)
  - The Echo Volume 3 Number 1, 1894 June (Volume 3, Issue 1)
  - The Echo Volume 3 Number 2, 1893 September (Volume 3, Issue 2)
  - The Echo Volume 3 Number 3, 1893 October (Volume 3, Issue 3)
  - The Echo Volume 3 Number 4, 1893 November (Volume 3, Issue 4)
  - The Echo Volume 3 Number 5, 1893 December (Volume 3, Issue 5)
  - The Echo Volume 3 Number 6, 1894 January (Volume 3, Issue 6)
  - The Echo Volume 3 Number 7, 1894 February (Volume 3, Issue 7)
  - The Echo Volume 3 Number 8, 1894 March (Volume 3, Issue 8)
  - The Echo Volume 3 Number 9, 1894 April (Volume 3, Issue 9)
  - The Echo Volume 3 Number 10, 1894 May (Volume 3, Issue 10)
  - The Echo Volume 4 Number 1, 1895 June (Volume 4, Issue 1)
  - The Echo Volume 4 Number 2, 1895 September (Volume 4, Issue 2)
  - The Echo Volume 4 Number 3, 1895 October (Volume 4, Issue 3)
  - The Echo Volume 4 Number 4, 1895 November (Volume 4, Issue 4)
  - The Echo Volume 4 Number 5, 1895 December (Volume 4, Issue 5)
  - The Echo Volume 4 Number 6, 1896 January (Volume 4, Issue 6)
  - The Echo Volume 4 Number 7, 1896 February (Volume 4, Issue 7)
  - The Echo Volume 4 Number 8, 1896 March (Volume 4, Issue 8)
  - The Echo Volume 4 Number 9, 1896 April (Volume 4, Issue 9)
  - The Echo Volume 4 Number 10, 1896 May (Volume 4, Issue 10)
  - The Echo Volume 5 Number 1, 1896 June (Volume 5, Issue 1)
  - The Echo Volume 5 Number 2, 1896 September (Volume 5, Issue 2)
  - The Echo Volume 5 Number 3, 1896 October (Volume 5, Issue 3)
  - The Echo Volume 5 Number 4, 1896 November (Volume 5, Issue 4)
  - The Echo Volume 5 Number 5, 1896 December (Volume 5, Issue 5)
  - The Echo Volume 5 Number 6, 1897 January (Volume 5, Issue 6)
  - The Echo Volume 5 Number 7, 1897 February (Volume 5, Issue 7)
  - The Echo Volume 5 Number 8, 1897 March (Volume 5, Issue 8)
  - The Echo Volume 5 Number 9, 1897 April (Volume 5, Issue 9)
  - The Echo Volume 5 Number 10, 1897 May (Volume 5, Issue 10)
  - The Echo Volume 6 Number 1, 1897 June (Volume 6, Issue 1)
  - The Echo Volume 6 Number 2, 1897 September (Volume 6, Issue 2)
  - The Echo Volume 6 Number 3, 1897 October (Volume 6, Issue 3)
  - The Echo Volume 6 Number 4, 1897 November (Volume 6, Issue 4)
  - The Echo Volume 6 Number 5, 1897 December (Volume 6, Issue 5)
  - The Echo Volume 6 Number 6, 1898 January (Volume 6, Issue 6)
  - The Echo Volume 6 Number 7, 1898 February (Volume 6, Issue 7)
  - The Echo Volume 6 Number 8, 1898 March (Volume 6, Issue 8)
  - The Echo Volume 6 Number 9, 1898 April (Volume 6, Issue 9)
  - The Echo Volume 6 Number 10, 1898 May (Volume 6, Issue 10)
  - The Echo Volume 6 Number 11, 1898 June (Volume 6, Issue 11)
  - The Echo Volume 7 Number 1, 1898 September (Volume 7, Issue 1)
  - The Echo Volume 7 Number 2, 1898 October (Volume 7, Issue 2)
  - The Echo Volume 7 Number 3, 1898 November (Volume 7, Issue 3)
  - The Echo Volume 7 Number 4, 1898 December (Volume 7, Issue 4)
  - The Echo Volume 7 Number 5, 1899 January (Volume 7, Issue 5)
  - The Echo Volume 7 Number 6, 1899 February (Volume 7, Issue 6)
  - The Echo Volume 7 Number 7, 1899 March (Volume 7, Issue 7)
  - The Echo Volume 7 Number 8, 1899 April (Volume 7, Issue 8)
  - The Echo Volume 7 Number 9, 1899 May (Volume 7, Issue 9)
  - The Echo Volume 7 Number 10, 1899 June (Volume 7, Issue 10)
  - The Echo Volume 8 Number 10, 1900 June (Box 1, Issue 1)
  - The Echo Volume 11 Number 5, 1903 January (Box 1, Issue 2)
  - The Echo Volume 12 Number 10, 1904 June (Box 1, Issue 3)
  - The Echo Volume 13 Number 1, 1904 September (Box 1, Issue 4)
  - The Echo Volume 13 Number 9, 1905 May (Box 1, Issue 5)
  - The Echo Volume 14 Number 5, 1906 January (Box 1, Issue 6)
  - The Echo Volume 15 Number 2, 1906 October (Box 1, Issue 7)
  - The Echo Volume 15 Number 4, 1906 December (Box 1, Issue 8)
  - The Echo Volume 15 Number 6, 1907 February (Box 1, Issue 9)
  - The Echo Volume 15 Number 7, 1907 March (Box 1, Issue 10)
  - The Echo Volume 15 Number 8, 1907 April (Box 1, Issue 11)
  - The Echo Volume 15 Number 9, 1907 May (Box 1, Issue 12)
  - The Echo Volume 16 Number 1, 1907 September (Box 1, Issue 13)
  - The Echo Volume 16 Number 2, 1907 October (Box 1, Issue 14)
  - The Echo Volume 16 Number 7, 1908 March (Box 1, Issue 15)
  - The Echo Volume 16 Number 8, 1908 April (Box 1, Issue 16)
  - The Echo Volume 16 Number 9, 1908 May (Box 1, Issue 17)
  - The Echo Volume 16 Number 10, 1908 June (Box 1, Issue 18)
  - The Echo Volume 17 Number 1, 1908 October (Box 1, Issue 19)
  - The Echo Volume 17 Number 2, 1908 November (Box 1, Issue 20)
  - The Echo Volume 17 Number 3, 1908 December (Box 1, Issue 21)
  - The Echo Volume 17 Number 4, 1909 January (Box 1, Issue 22)
  - The Echo Volume 17 Number 5, 1909 February (Box 1, Issue 23)
  - The Echo Volume 17 Number 7, 1909 April (Box 1, Issue 24)
  - The Echo Volume 17 Number 8, 1909 May (Box 1, Issue 25)
  - The Echo Volume 17 Number 9, 1909 June (Box 1, Issue 26)
  - The Echo Volume 18 Number 1, 1909 October (Box 1, Issue 27)
  - The Echo Volume 18 Number 2, 1909 November (Box 1, Issue 28)
  - The Echo Volume 18 Number 3, 1909 December (Box 1, Issue 29)
  - The Echo Volume 18 Number 4, 1910 January (Box 1, Issue 30)
  - The echo volume 18 Number 5, 1910 February (Box 1, Issue 31)
  - The Echo Volume 18 Number 6, 1910 March (Box 1, Issue 32)
  - The Echo Volume 18 Number 7, 1910 April (Box 1, Issue 33)
  - The Echo Volume 18 Number 8, 1910 May-1910 June (Box 2, Issue 1)
  - The Echo Volume 19 Number 1, 1910 September (Box 2, Issue 2)
  - The Echo Volume 19 Number 2, 1910 October (Box 2, Issue 3)
  - The Echo Voume 19 Number 3, 1910 November (Box 2, Issue 4)
  - The Echo Volume 19 Number 4, 1910 December (Box 2, Issue 5)
  - The Echo Volume 20 Number 5, 1911 January (Box 2, Issue 6)
  - The Echo Volume 19 Number 6, 1911 February (Box 2, Issue 7)
  - The Echo Volume 19 Number 7, 1911 March (Box 2, Issue 8)
  - The Echo Volume 19 Number 8, 1911 June (Box 2, Issue 9)
  - The Echo Volume 21 Number 2, 1911 October (Box 2, Issue 10)
  - The Echo Volume 21 Number 3, 1911 November (Box 2, Issue 11)
  - The Echo Volume 21 Number 4, 1911 December (Box 2, Issue 12)
  - The Echo Volume 21 Number 5, 1912 January (Box 2, Issue 13)
  - The Echo Volume 21 Number 6, 1912 February (Box 2, Issue 14)
  - The Echo Volume 21 Number 7, 1912 March (Box 2, Issue 15)
  - The Echo Volume 21 Number 8, 1912 April (Box 2, Issue 16)
  - The Echo Volume 21 Number 9, 1912 May (Box 2, Issue 17)
  - The Echo Volume 21 Number 10, 1912 June (Box 2, Issue 18)
  - The Echo Volume 22 Number 1, 1912 September (Box 2, Issue 19)
  - The Echo Volume 22 Number 2, 1912 October (Box 2, Issue 20)
  - The Echo Volume 22 Number 3, 1912 November (Box 2, Issue 21)
  - The Echo Volume 22 Number 4, 1912 December (Box 2, Issue 22)
  - The Echo Volume 22 Number 5, 1913 January (Box 2, Issue 23)
  - The Echo Volume 22 Number 6, 1913 February (Box 2, Issue 24)
  - The Echo Volume 22 Number 7, 1913 March (Box 2, Issue 25)
  - The Echo Volume 22 Number 8, 1913 April (Box 2, Issue 26)
  - The Echo Volume 22 Number 9, 1913 May (Box 2, Issue 27)
  - The Echo Volume 23 Number 1, 1913 September (Box 2, Issue 28)
  - The Echo Volume 23 Number 3, 1913 November (Box 3, Issue 1)
  - The Echo Volume 23 Number 4, 1913 December (Box 3, Issue 2)
  - The Echo Volume 23 Number 5, 1914 January (Box 3, Issue 3)
  - The Echo Volume 23 Number 6, 1914 February (Box 3, Issue 4)
  - The Echo Volume 23 Number 8, 1914 April (Box 3, Issue 5)
  - The Echo Volume 24 Number 1, 1914 September (Box 3, Issue 6)
  - The Echo Volume 24 Number 2, 1914 October (Box 3, Issue 7)
  - The Echo Volume 24 Number 6, 1915 February (Box 3, Issue 8)
  - The Echo Volume 24 Number 9, 1915 May (Box 3, Issue 9)
  - The Echo Volume 25 Number 1, 1915 September (Box 3, Issue 10)
  - The Echo Volume 25 Number 2, 1915 October (Box 3, Issue 11)
  - The Echo Volume 25 Number 3, 1915 November (Box 3, Issue 12)
  - The Echo Volume 25 Number 4, 1915 December (Box 3, Issue 13)
  - The Echo Volume 25 Number 5, 1916 January (Box 3, Issue 14)
  - The Echo Volume 25 Number 6, 1916 February (Box 3, Issue 15)
  - The Echo Volume 25 Number 7, 1916 March (Box 3, Issue 16)
  - The Echo Volume 25 Number 8, 1916 April (Box 3, Issue 17)
  - The Echo Volume 25 Number 9, 1916 May (Box 3, Issue 18)
  - The Echo Volume 26 Number 1, 1916 October (Volume 26, Issue 1)
  - The Echo Volume 26 Number 2, 1916 November (Volume 26, Issue 2)
  - The Echo Volume 26 Number 3, 1916 December (Volume 26, Issue 3)
  - The Echo Volume 26 Number 4, 1917 January (Volume 26, Issue 4)
  - The Echo Volume 26 Number 5, 1917 February (Volume 26, Issue 5)
  - The Echo Volume 26 Number 6, 1917 March (Volume 26, Issue 6)
  - The Echo Volume 26 Number 7, 1917 April (Volume 26, Issue 7)
  - The Echo Volume 26 Number 8, 1917 June (Volume 26, Issue 8)
  - The Echo Volume 27 Number 1, 1917 October (Volume 27, Issue 1)
  - The Echo Volume 27 Number 2, 1917 November (Volume 27, Issue 2)
  - The Echo Volume 27 Number 3, 1917 December (Volume 27, Issue 3)
  - The Echo Volume 27 Number 4, 1918 January (Volume 27, Issue 4)
  - The Echo Volume 27 Number 5, 1918 February (Volume 27, Issue 5)
  - The Echo Volume 27 Number 6, 1918 March (Volume 27, Issue 6)
  - The Echo Volume 27 Number 7, 1918 April (Volume 27, Issue 7)
  - The Echo Volume 27 Number 8, 1918 May (Volume 27, Issue 8)
  - The Echo Volume 27 Number 9, 1918 June (Volume 27, Issue 9)
  - State College Quarterly Volume 1 Number 1, 1918 December (Volume 1, Issue 1)
  - State College Quarterly Volume 1 Number 2, 1919 January (Volume 1, Issue 2)
  - State College Quarterly Volume 1 Number 3, 1919 March (Volume 1, Issue 3)
  - State College Quarterly Volume 1 Number 4, 1919 June (Volume 1, Issue 4)
  - State College Quarterly Volume 2 Number 1, 1919 November (Volume 2, Issue 1)
  - State College Quarterly Volume 2 Number 2, 1920 January (Volume 2, Issue 2)
  - State College Quarterly Volume 2 Number 3, 1920 March (Volume 2, Issue 3)
  - State College Quarterly Volume 2 Number 4, 1920 June (Volume 2, Issue 4)
  - State College Quarterly Volume 3 Number 1, 1920 November (Volume 3, Issue 1)
  - State College Quarterly Volume 3 Number 2, 1921 January (Volume 3, Issue 2)
  - State College Quarterly Volume 3 Number 3, 1921 March (Volume 3, Issue 3)
  - State College Quarterly Volume 4 Number 1, 1921 Novemebr (Volume 4, Issue 1)
  - State College Quarterly Volume 4 Number 2, 1922 January (Volume 4, Issue 2)
  - State College Quarterly Volume 4 Number 3, 1922 March (Volume 4, Issue 3)
  - State College Quarterly Volume 4 Number 4, 1922 June (Volume 4, Issue 4)
  - State College Quarterly Volume 5 Number 1, 1922 November (Volume 5, Issue 1)
  - State College Quarterly Volume 5 Number 2, 1923 February (Volume 5, Issue 2)
  - State College Quarterly Volume 5 Number 3, 1923 April (Volume 5, Issue 3)
  - State College Quarterly Volume 5 Number 4, 1923 June (Volume 5, Issue 4)
  - State College Quarterly Volume 6 Number 1, 1923 November (Volume 6, Issue 1)
  - State College Quarterly Volume 6 Number 2, 1924 March (Volume 6, Issue 2)
  - State College Quarterly Volume 6 Number 3, 1924 April (Volume 6, Issue 3)
  - State College Quarterly Volume 6 Number 4, 1923 June (Volume 6, Issue 4)
  - State College Quarterly Volume 7 Number 1, 1924 November (Volume 7, Issue 1)
  - State College Quarterly Volume 7 Number 2, 1925 April (Volume 7, Issue 2)
  - State College Quarterly Volume 7 Number 3, 1925 June (Volume 7, Issue 3)
  - State College Quarterly Volume 8 Number 1, 1925 November (Volume 8, Issue 1)
  - State College Quarterly Volume 8 Number 2, 1926 February (Volume 8, Issue 2)
  - State College Quarterly Volume 8 Number 3, 1926 April (Volume 8, Issue 3)
  - State College Quarterly Volume 8 Number 4, 1926 June (Volume 8, Issue 4)
  - State College Quarterly Volume 9 Number 1, 1926 November (Volume 9, Issue 1)
  - State College Quarterly Volume 9 Number 2, 1927 March (Volume 9, Issue 2)
  - State College Quarterly Volume 9 Number 3, 1927 April (Volume 9, Issue 3)
  - State College Quarterly Volume 9 Number 4, 1927 June (Volume 9, Issue 4)
  - State College Quarterly Volume 10 Number 1, 1927 October (Volume 10, Issue 1)
  - State College Quarterly Volume 10 Number 2, 1928 January (Volume 10, Issue 2)
  - State College Quarterly Volume 10 Number 3, 1928 March (Volume 10, Issue 3)
  - State College Quarterly Volume 10 Number 4, 1928 June (Volume 10, Issue 4)
  - State College Echo Volume 11 Number 1, 1928 November (Volume 11, Issue 1)
  - State College Echo Volume 11 Number 2, 1929 January (Volume 11, Issue 2)
  - State College Echo Volume 11 Number 3, 1929 April (Volume 11, Issue 3)
  - State College Echo Volume 11 Number 4, 1929 June (Volume 11, Issue 4)
  - State College Echo Volume 12 Number 1, 1929 November (Volume 12, Issue 1)
  - State College Echo Volume 12 Number 2, 1930 February (Volume 12, Issue 2)
  - State College Echo Volume 12 Number 3, 1930 April (Volume 12, Issue 3)
  - State College Echo Volume 12 Number 4, 1930 June (Volume 12, Issue 4)
  - State College Echo Volume 13 Number 1, 1930 November (Volume 13, Issue 1)
  - State College Echo Volume 13 Number 2, 1931 February (Volume 13, Issue 2)
  - State College Echo Volume 13 Number 3, 1931 April (Volume 13, Issue 3)
  - State College Echo Volume 13 Number 4, 1931 June (Volume 13, Issue 4)
  - State College Echo Volume 14 Number 1, 1931 November (Volume 14, Issue 1)
  - State College Echo Volume 14 Number 2, 1932 February (Volume 14, Issue 2)
  - State College Echo Volume 14 Number 3, 1932 April (Volume 14, Issue 3)
  - State College Echo Volume 15 Number 1, 1932 November (Volume 15, Issue 1)
  - State College Echo Volume 15 Number 2, 1933 February (Volume 15, Issue 2)
  - State College Echo Volume 15 Number 3, 1933 May (Volume 15, Issue 3)
  - State College Echo Volume 16 Number 1, 1933 November (Volume 16, Issue 1)
  - State College Echo Volume 16 Number 2, 1934 May (Volume 16, Issue 2)
  - State College Echo Volume 17 Number 1, 1934 November (Volume 17, Issue 1)
  - State College Echo Volume 17 Number 2, 1935 May (Volume 17, Issue 2)
  - State College Echo Volume 18 Number 1, 1935 November (Volume 18, Issue 1)
  - State College Echo Volume 18 Number 2, 1936 March (Volume 18, Issue 2)
  - State College Echo Volume 18 Number 3, 1936 May (Volume 18, Issue 3)
  - State College Echo Volume 19 Number 1, 1936 December (Volume 19, Issue 1)
  - State College Echo Volume 19 Number 2, 1937 February (Volume 19, Issue 2)
  - State College Echo Volume 19 Number 3, 1937 April (Volume 19, Issue 3)
  - State College Echo Volume 20 Number 1, 1937 December (Volume 20, Issue 1)
  - State College Echo Volume 20 Number 2, 1938 February (Volume 20, Issue 2)
  - State College Echo Volume 20 Number 3, 1938 May (Volume 20, Issue 3)
  - State College Echo Volume 21 Number 1, 1938 December (Volume 21, Issue 1)
  - State College Echo Volume 21 Number 2, 1939 February (Volume 21, Issue 2)
  - State College Echo Volume 21 Number 3, 1939 April (Volume 21, Issue 3)